yvesrocherusa.com 2005-12-20

# Yves Rocher - your natural beauty source for cosmetics, fragrance, skin and body care

 |  PRIVACY POLICY - OUR PLEDGE TO YOU

Yves Rocher's Privacy Pledge

We appreciate the confidence you place in us when you trust your beauty care needs to Yves Rocher. Relationships are important to us, and we take our relationship with you very seriously. We respect your privacy, and pledge to handle any personal information you give us with utmost care.

Any information Yves Rocher collects from you is gathered for the purpose of providing you with our service. For example, we store your shipping address in order to send you any products you purchase from us. We also keep record of the products you purchase and the purchase amount, should you ever need to make a return or exchange. We will not give any of your personally identifiable information to any other company. 

Yves Rocher takes special security measures to protect the personally identifiable information that we store. This means, for example, that we use appropriate software and hardware tools to protect our computers against unauthorized access. We also restrict our employees' ability to access your personally identifiable information.

More specific details about our privacy policy:  
The types of information that are collected

As part of our service to you, we receive and store any information you relay to us through our Web site and any information your browser gives to us. The exact information we collect may vary from user to user, but the information we collect might include your name, your phone number, your E-mail address, the Internet Protocol (IP) addresses you use to contact our site, your user name and password for this site, your shipping and billing address, your computer and connection information such as browser type and version, your operating system, the web address that referred you to our site, your buying history, and the phone number you use to call our toll-free telephone number.

You may choose not to relay certain information to us. However, you may not be able to take advantage of some features of our web site if you do not give us information required by those features.

Like many web sites, we use "cookies," which are combinations of letters and numbers given to a Web browser by a Web server, and then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server for the purpose of identifying the user visiting the site. If you do not wish to receive cookies from our site, you can configure your web browser to reject them, or use a utility designed to help you visit Web sites anonymously. 

We may also receive information from other sources about you and add it to the information we store about you. For example, we sometimes receive updated delivery and address information from our delivery companies, which we store in order to better serve you in the future.

A Special Note about Children

We do not gather any personally identifiable information from children whom we know are under the age of 13. We believe strongly that parents should play an integral part in their child's on-line experience and should monitor that activity to ensure on-line sites are respecting their child's privacy.

The use the personal information gathered

As noted, most of the information we collect is gathered for purposes of providing you with our service. For example, we store your shipping address in order to send you any products you purchase from us. In addition, we may aggregate data we collect on the use of the service to improve and maintain the service, or for marketing activities. However, such uses will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information.

In an effort to offer you the most current shopping opportunities, we may contact you by email with news about Yves Rocher products, service, and events. You will only receive these emails if you have subscribed to receive them or if you have placed an order from our website. If you do not wish to receive these E-mails, please contact us at info@YvesRocherUSA.com. or simply unsubscribe through the links included in any E-mails received by you from Yves Rocher.

In general, we will not give any of your personally identifiable information (including your E-mail address) to any other company (except for our corporate parents and subsidiaries, and companies controlled by or under common control with YvesRocherUSA.com), unless required to do so by law. However, there are some circumstances in which we may be required to disclose your personally identifiable information to third parties, and we want you to know about them.

The sharing of personal information

First, we will sometimes employ other companies to perform functions on our behalf, such as fulfilling orders, delivering packages, providing customer service, sending mail or E-mail, processing credit card payments, and other functions necessary to our business. When we share your information with these companies, we will give them access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but we will not grant them permission to use that information for any other purposes.

Second, we may reveal a user's identity (or whatever information we know about that individual) if we believe that user is harming or interfering with Yves Rocher's property, or with other Yves Rocher users or anyone else, or violating (either intentionally or unintentionally) any law, regulation or our Terms of Use, or any of Yves Rocher's rights, including intellectual property rights.

Third, Yves Rocher will reveal information, including personally identifiable information, to the extent Yves Rocher reasonably believes it is required to do so by law.

Fourth, Yves-RocherUSA.com may transfer information it collects, including any personally identifiable information, in the course of a sale of all or a significant part of the assets of the company or if we enter into an alliance or joint venture with other companies to co-brand, co-market or otherwise promote the sale of Yves Rocher and other products or services.

Fifth, Yves Rocher may also disclose your personally identifiable information with your express consent. If we seek that consent, we will do so unambiguously, explaining precisely what information we seek to disclose, the entity to whom we wish to disclose it, and the purpose for the disclosure.

Security and protection of personal information

We take special security measures to protect the personally identifiable information that we store. This means, for example, that we use appropriate software and hardware tools to protect our computers against unauthorized access. We also restrict our employees' ability to access your personally identifiable information.
